Fred Allen Radio Scripts
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Fred Allen Radio Scripts 1934-1949
MSS10462
Allen, Fred, 1894-1956
400 items 18 containers 7.2 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Radio comedian and humorist. Copyright deposits of radio scripts of Allen’s radio programs.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Allen, Fred, 1894-1956.; Bankhead, Tallulah, 1902-1968.; Benny, Jack, 1894-1974.; Crosby, Bing, 1903-1977.; Hope, Bob, 1903-2003.; Morgan, Henry, 1915-1994.
Subjects
American wit and humor.; Radio programs.; Radio scripts.
Titles
Bing Crosby show (Radio program); Bob Hope show (Radio program); Chesterfield supper club (Radio program); Henry Morgan show (Radio program); Jack Benny program (Radio program); The big show (Radio program); Town hall tonight (Radio program)
Occupations
Comedians.; Humorists.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The radio scripts of Fred Allen, radio comedian and humorist, were transferred from the Copyright Office of the Library of Congress in 1966.
Access and Restrictions
Restrictions apply governing the use, photoduplication, or publication of items in this collection. Consult a reference librarian in the Manuscript Division for information concerning these restrictions. In addition, many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1894, May 31 Born John Florence Sullivan, Cambridge, Mass.
circa 1927-1928 Married Portland Hoffa
1915-1916 Worked in vaudeville as a juggler, touring the United States, Canada, and Australia, sometimes appearing as Fred St. James and Fred James
1939-1949 Wrote, produced, and starred in The Fred Allen Show radio program
1944 Received George Foster Peabody Broadcasting Award
1953-1954 Host, Judge for Yourself (also known as The Fred Allen Show), NBC Television
1954-1956 Panelist, What's My Line? CBS Television
1956, Mar. 17 Died, New York, N.Y.
Scope and Content Note
The radio scripts of Fred Allen (1894-1956) span the years 1934-1949 and consist of copyright deposits of radio scripts and broadcasts for Town Hall Tonight, The Chesterfield Supper Club, the Jack Benny Show, Bing Crosby Show, Bob Hope Show, and Henry Morgan Show, and Talullah Bankhead's program, The Big Show. The collection is arranged by date of copyright.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged chronologically.
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm78010462
Container List
- Radio scripts (Box 1)
  - 1934, Nov.13-1938, June 9 (Box 1)
  - 1938, July 9-1939, 26 Jan. (Box 2)
  - 1939, Jan. 26-July 12 (Box 3)
  - 1939, Nov. 7-1940, Apr. 5 (Box 4)
  - 1940, Apr. 5-June 8 (Box 5)
  - 1940, Oct. 7-1941, Feb. 14 (Box 6)
  - 1941, Mar. 8-July 1 (Box 7)
  - 1941, Oct. 10-1942, Jan. 8 (Box 8)
  - 1942, Jan. 13-Apr. 29 (Box 9)
  - 1942, May 7-1943, Jan. 5 (Box 10)
  - 1943, Jan. 6-Dec. 27 (Box 11)
  - 1943, Dec. 27-1944, July 1 (Box 12)
  - 1946, Jan. 4-May 30 (Box 13)
  - 1946, June 7-1947, Feb. 2 (Box 14)
  - 1947, Feb. 23-1948, Feb. 4 (Box 15)
  - 1948, Mar. 3-July 8 (Box 16)
  - 1948, Nov. 1-1949, Mar. 9 (Box 17)
  - 1949, Mar. 18 July 6 (Box 18)